准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
证人保护计划
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
完美
Perfect
晚上好  邻居
Evening, neighbor
晚上好  普雷斯顿
Evening, Preston
祝你今晚音乐会演出顺利
Good luck at the concert tonight
谢谢  塞巴斯蒂安
Thank you, Sebastian
你们也许自以为认识我
You may think you know me
其实不然
but you don't
我曾经是章鱼哥
I used to be Squidward Tentacles
而如今  我名叫
but now, the name's
今晚
约翰海豚
[ 改自John Doe，指代身份不明的人 ]
海豚  约翰海豚
Dolphin, John Dolphin
是约翰海豚
It's John Dolphin
我在纽开普市拥有了美妙的新生活
I have a wonderful new life in New Kelp City
究竟怎么会这样呢
How did this happen?
且听我分解
Well, I'll tell you
一天  我这辈子最糟糕的事
One day, the worst thing that ever happened to me
音乐
最终却变成了
turned out to be
我这辈子最美好的事
the best thing that ever happened to me
不好意思
Excuse me
我要投诉
I'd like to lodge a complaint
这簧片有毛病
This reed is defective
抱歉  先生
I'm sorry, sir
我们库存就只剩这片簧片了
but that's the only reed we have in stock
有没有考虑过演奏安全点的乐器
Have you ever thought of playing something safer
比如说三角铁
like the triangle?
我这可是抢劫
This is a stickup
把店里的钱全都交出来
Give me all the dough in the joint
不然我就擦掉你们
or I'll rub you out
是埃莫橡皮擦
Elmer Eraser
要是你们哪个白痴敢告密
If either of you bozos squeal
我一定会找到你
I'll track ya down
把你给擦了
and rub you out
我一个字都不会说
I won't say a syllable
谅你也不敢  否则我一定会找到你
See that you don't, or Elmer Eraser will find you
警察试图让我开口
The police tried to get me to talk
然而我没兴趣
but I wasn't interested
至少起先如此
at first
都说了  我什么都没看到
I told you, I didn't see a thing
放心  章鱼哥先生
Not to worry, Mr. Tentacles
如果你想起了什么事
If you do remember anything
我们可以把你纳入证人保护计划
we can put you into witness protection
当然  也只能把你搬到别处
Of course, we'll have to move you to a new town
给你换个假名  安排新工作
change your name, and give you a new job
听好警官  我绝对不招
Look, officer, I'm not talking
可惜你就再也见不到你朋友跟邻居了
Unfortunately, you'll never see
your friends or neighbors again
我全都看到了
I saw everything
我来作证
I'll testify
如今  我拥有了梦寐以求的一切
Now, I have everything I'd ever dreamed of
我一定是出幻觉了
I must be imagining things
后台入口
不可能会有这种事
This can't be happening
我们想你  章鱼哥
We miss you, Squidward
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
放心
Don't worry
交给我
I've got it
好爱你的新胡子
Love your new beard
谢了  不过这胡子是假的
Thanks, but it's only a fake one
海绵宝宝跟派大星
SpongeBob and Patrick?
你们俩白痴咋找到我的
How did you two goofballs find me?
想知道我们是咋找到你的吗  章鱼哥
You like to know how we found you, Squidward?
你声音从哪冒出来的
Where's your voice coming from?
那是蟹堡王寻常的一天
It was an average day at the old Krusty Krab
但是某样东西失踪了
But something was missing
或者应该说是  某个人
Or should I say "someone"?
在吗
Hello?
里面有人在吗
Anybody home?
天啊  这里的服务
Boy, the service here
越来越走下坡路了  海绵宝宝
is really going downhill, SpongeBob
章鱼哥还没来吗
Squidward's still not here?
看来怪不得
I guess that would explain
我好几周都没有收到点餐单
why I haven't had a single order in weeks
我也好几周都没见到他在家了
I haven't seen him in his house for weeks either
更没见到他泡浴缸
not even in his bathtub
而且他冰箱也没吃的了
And his fridge is out of food
我真想我最爱的邻居
I really miss my favorite neighbor
可我就在这啊  兄弟
But I'm right here, buddy
谢天谢地
Thank goodness
可是要怎么找到章鱼哥呢
But how do we find Squidward?
放心
Don't worry
交给我
I got this
现在只要有味道像章鱼哥的东西就行
Now, I just need something that smells like Squidward
来片他的旧竖笛簧片应该可以
One of his old clarinet reeds should help
找到了
Got it
蟹堡王
于是  我们跟着气味
And so, we followed the scent
来到了你新家的大门
to your new front door
为什么要离开我们  章鱼哥
Why did you leave us, Squidward?
你们两个傻子会全都搞砸的
You knuckleheads are gonna ruin everything
我可是纳入了证人保护计划
I'm in witness protection
健身染毒计划
Fitness infection?
我这是在躲埃莫橡皮擦
I'm hiding out from Elmer Eraser
埃莫橡皮擦
Elmer Eraser?
那个爱擦告密者的抢匪吗
The robber who relishes in rubbing out rats?
你们两个能不能快滚
Would you two get lost?
不然会引狼入室  害我被抓包
You're gonna lead that maniac right to me
我都不知道章鱼哥进了蠢人完护计划
I had no idea Squidward was in witless perfection
差点就害他暴露了
And we almost blew his cover
刚刚真抱歉
Sorry about that
没看到你们在那
I didn't see ya there
你那个橡皮擦挺好看的嘛
Say, that sure is a nice eraser
谢了
Thanks
我妈给我做的
My mommy made it for me
橡皮擦
Eraser
让我想起来件事  是什么呢
That reminds me of something, but what?
你们两个呆子知道要上哪去找
Do you bozos know where I can find
关键证人
这个笨蛋吗
this mug?
埃莫橡皮擦
Elmer Eraser?
那不是杯子
That's not a mug
笨 蛋
是
That's
我们这辈子从来没见过那位
We've never seen that person in our entire lives
不管他长没长胡子
with or without a beard
要是你们见过
Well, if you do
就麻烦你们告诉我
please let me know
派大星  那个就是埃莫橡皮擦
Patrick, that was Elmer Eraser
谁啊
Who?
必须警告章鱼哥
We gotta warn Squidward
感谢海神王  那俩白痴走了
Thank Neptune those idiots are gone
章鱼哥
Squidward
结果又回来了
And they're back
猜猜我们在外面看到谁了
Guess who we saw outside?
埃莫橡皮擦
Elmer Eraser
什么
What?
我完蛋了
I'm doomed
放心
Don't worry
我们要把你纳入证人保护保护计划
We'll put you into witness protection protection
你有我们保护很安全
You're safe with us
这边这个藏身处有很多自然光
Here's a hideout with a lot of natural light
玻璃屋吗
A glass house?
你们疯了吗
Are you nuts?
这样就看得到埃莫橡皮擦过来了
This way, you can see Elmer Eraser coming
可他也看得到我啊
But he can see me too
你
You
你们骗了我
You guys lied to me
那就是章鱼哥
That's Squidward
放心
Don't worry
我来解决他
I got him
等等
Wait
不要
Don't
原来这是有机玻璃屋
It's a plexiglass house
完美
Perfect
我们可以开得远远的
We can drive far, far away
垃圾场
抓到了
Gotcha
大家跳船啊
Everybody jump
这样逃脱才对嘛
This is how you make a getaway
等等
Wait
快
Quick
进去
In there
爬上去
Up there
你在这里就安全了
You'll be safe in here
抓到了
Gotcha
章鱼哥没了保护
Squidward is unprotected
上来
Hop on
我们会救你的  章鱼哥
We'll save you, Squidward
不好
Oh, no
那两个白痴找到我了
Those two halfwits found me
原来只是埃莫橡皮擦
It's just Elmer Eraser
埃莫橡皮擦
Elmer Eraser
我们会保护你的  章鱼哥
We'll protect you, Squidward
抓到了
Gotcha
求你了  埃莫橡皮擦
Please, Elmer Eraser
别把章鱼哥擦了啊
don't rub out Squidward
放心
Don't worry
我不是埃莫
I'm not Elmer
我是侦探橡皮擦
I'm Detective Eraser
裤头村警察局
埃莫是我的双胞胎兄弟
Elmer's my twin brother
我整天都在找你呢
I've been trying to find you all day
谢天谢地
Thank goodness
你能不能逮捕那两个傻子
Can you arrest these two blockheads
让我继续过上约翰海豚的美好生活
so I can go back to being John Dolphin?
告诉你个好消息
Lucky for you
我兄弟埃莫已经被抓去坐牢了
my brother Elmer has been caught and put in jail
你再也不需要证人保护计划了
You don't need witness protection anymore
是不是很棒  章鱼哥
Isn't it great, Squidward?
你可以回裤头村陪我们了
You can come back to Bikini Bottom with us
章鱼哥回来了
Squidward's back
真棒啊
Wonderful
章鱼哥回来了
Squidward's back
你当鬼
You're it
不对  你当鬼
No, you're it
章鱼哥当鬼
Squidward's it
不对  你当鬼
No, you're it
我总算安全了
I was finally safe
但我即将目击又一桩罪案
but I was about to become witness to another crime
一桩我即将犯下的罪案
a crime I was going to commit
我要把你们都擦了
I'm going to rub you out
擦
Rub
树屋隔离
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
坚果谷仓
天啊  刚刚在坚果谷仓好个大买特买
Boy, that was one heck of a shoppin' spree
down at the old Nut Barn
不过很值得
Worth it, though
嘎嘣脆的坚果真好吃
These cracklin' nuts taste so good
就好像我嘴里开了个民歌演唱会似的
it's like there's a hootenanny in my mouth
那玩意哪来
Where'd that come fr
我头盔就快跟鸡蛋似的碎掉了
My helmet's about to crack like an egg
必须尽快回树屋里
I gotta get home to my dome ASAP
刚刚真是好险啊
That was a close shave
最好找出我的备用头盔
Better dig out my backup helmet
一定是我手指沾到的坚果灰害的
Must be all that nut dust on my fingers
看来我一个头盔都不剩了
Looks like I'm plumb out of helmets
最好去订购个新的
Better order a new one
头盔专线
喂
Hello?
头盔专线吗
Helmets Direct?
对  我要再买一个
Yeah, I need another one
要多大的尺寸
What size do you need?
尺寸
Size?
松鼠中号
Squirrel medium
我们中号卖光了
We're out of size medium
只能特别定制
I'll have to special order it
得要六到八周才能送达
It's gonna take six to eight weeks to get it
六到八周吗
Six to eight weeks?
看来我只能困在这里一阵子了
Looks like I'm stuck inside for a while
不过能做的事有不少呢
But I got plenty to do
才过了一小时
It's only been one hour
我就已经受不了了
but I can't take it anymore
要是再看不到一只活物
If I don't see another living critter soon
我就要疯了
I'm gonna go nuts
疯了
Nuts
坚 果
没事  珊迪
Hey, now, Sandy
你不会疯的
You'd never go nuts
你可是牢牢把握着现实呢
Your grip on reality is too firm
谢了  坚果兄弟
Thanks, Nutty Buddy
你总能在我身边挺我
You're always here for me
朋友就该互帮互助
That's what friends are for
也许我可以把谁给套过来
Maybe I can lasso someone into coming over
发出很多邀请后
我就不懂了
I don't understand
怎么个个周二下午两点半都没空
How can everyone be busy at 2:30 on a Tuesday?
有了
I know
要是我没办法让朋友来看望我
If I can't get my friends to visit me
我就自己看望他们
I'll visit them
远程看望
remotely
你能行的
You got this
你行的
You got it
简直是刺激得不得了啊
Well, that's about as exciting as riding a no-legged bull
下一个
Next
墙
非常好
Very good
现在试试看侧方停船
Now, let's try parallel parking
救生员
举
And
完了
done
现在换这只手举一万下
Now, for 10,000 with this arm
一
One
二
Two
三
Three
简直害得我眼皮
This is making my eyelids
比拉里的杠铃还难抬
feel heavier than Larry's weights
下一个
Next
数完了
And done
现在换这只手数一万张
Now for 10,000 with this arm
一
One
二
Two
三
Three
四
Four
五
Five
裤头村里肯定有什么趣事可以看
There's gotta be something interesting
蟹堡王
to look at in this town
怎么会
What in the?
果不其然
Of course
是我先前撞到的那个巨大金属玩意
That big old metal whatsit I ran into
痞老板
Plankton?
最好凑近一点看看
Better go in for a closer look
什么声音这么吵
What's that noise?
我不会又一整晚没关凯伦了吧
Did I leave Karen on all night again?
今年的蚊子真是越来越大了
Mosquitos sure are getting big this year
可恶的痞老板
Dang that Plankton
我得查清楚他有什么打算
Now I gotta figure out what he's up to
喂
Yello?
喂  海绵宝宝
Heya, SpongeBob
我手头上有一点调查的工作
I'm in the middle of an investigation
希望你可以帮我稍微侦察一下
and I was hoping you could do
a little reconnoitering for me
天啊  珊迪
Gosh, Sandy
虽然我很愿意
I'd love to
但我已经在帮蟹老板侦察新芥末矿了
but I'm already reconnoitering
a new mustard mine for Mr. Krabs
我懂
I get it
你没空
You're busy
这种事没必要大吼大叫
You don't have to holler about it
喂
Hello?
喂  派大星
Howdy, Patrick
我要偷窥痞老板的诡计
I'm trying to peep Plankton's plans
能来帮忙吗
Wanna help out?
好啊
Sure
等我吃完三明治就来
I'll be over as soon as I finish my sandwich
好
Okay
好了  派大星
All right, Patrick
这任务应该够简单了
This should be simple enough
痞老板在建造某种邪恶装置
Plankton is building some sort of evil device
你就只要带着我的摄像机过去
All you gotta do is head over there with my camera
然后看一眼就行
and give it a look 'fer
有没有收到
Roger?
看一眼
A look 'fer
收到
Roger
你这是
Whatcha
在干什么  派大星
doin' there, Patrick?
在找罗杰
Looking for Roger
收 到
我给你帮一把得了
Let me give you a little help
海之霸
凯伦  我去买咖啡跟油煎饼了
Karen, I'm going out for coffee and crullers
正好
Perfect
趁痞老板不在  四处张望
Snoop around while Plankton's gone
天啊
Oh, boy
我就爱张望
I love snooping
张望张望张张望望
Snoop, snoop, snooper snoop, snoopy snoop
张大眼睛找线索
Keep your eyes peeled for a clue
用它看出来痞老板有什么打算
that might tell us what he's up to
蓝图  存储卡
Blueprints, memory cards
微缩胶片
microfiche
我找到东西了
I found something
是不是线索
Is it a clue?
对
Yeah
还可好吃了
A delicious one
是他午饭
It's his lunch
派大星  那不是线索
Patrick, that ain't a clue
是个小卷饼
That's a tiny burrito
好好好
Okay, okay
快来  罗杰罗杰
Here, Roger, Roger
根本就没东西
There's nothing here
只有这一整个破盒子的
Just this dumb old box of
金不木奉
"puh-loo-toe-ni-um"
钚棒
管他呢
Who cares?
钚棒
Plutonium?
痞老板一定是在建造某种核武器
Plankton must be building some sort of atomic weapon
而且还剑指蟹堡王
And it's pointed right at the Krusty Krab
蟹堡王
派大星  你的使命完成了
All right, Patrick, you've done your part
这些荧光棒害我骨头痒死了
These glow sticks make my bones itchy
我现在要用激光射他
Now I'm gonna zap him with my laser
先预热一下
She's warming up now
不好
Oh, no
痞老板回来了
Plankton's back
派大星  快撤啊
Patrick, you gotta get outta there
别被他给看到了
Don't let him see you
快
Hurry
我要迎风而上
I am like unto the wind
你来这干什么  白痴
What are you doing here, bozo?
我名字叫派大星
My name's Patrick
不叫白痴
not Bozo
废话  大侦探
Yeah, no duh, Sherlock
我名字叫白痴  不叫大侦探
My name's Bozo, not Sherlock
不好
Oh, no
被他发现了
He's onto us
该亮出武器了
Time to take out that weapon
我知道你名字  笨蛋
I know your name, ding dong
我名字叫大侦探  不叫笨蛋
My name's Sherlock, not Ding Dong
够了
Enough
没关系
It doesn't matter
就让你第一个见证我的邪恶新发明
You're gonna be the first
to witness my latest evil invention
快来海之霸用餐
"Eat at the Chum Bucket"
就只是个破广告牌吗
It's just a dumb, old sign?
才不邪恶呢
That's not evil
钚棒的来源不怎么符合道德标准
Well, the plutonium wasn't sourced ethically
算是有点邪恶吧
so it's a little evil
天啊
Boy
我怎么没想到呢
Why didn't I think of that?
看招  老螃蟹
Eat that, Krabs
六到八周后
谢谢你帮我开餐厅
Thanks for hosting me restaurant
毕竟蟹堡王坏了  还在维修
while the Krusty Krab is being repaired
海绵宝宝又被大猩猩弄伤  还在休养
and while SpongeBob's recovering
from his gorilla injuries
尽一点绵薄之力而已
It's the least I could do
我的头盔
My helmet
终于来了
Finally
我的新餐厅
Me new restaurant
终于来了
Finally
别闲逛了  章鱼哥先生
Quit yer loafin', Mr. Squidward
快去搬蟹堡王
Ya got a buildin' to move
还要再待树屋里六到八周吗
Six to eight more weeks on the inside?
你要不要来接下一班啊  坚果兄弟
How-how about you take the next shift, Nutty Buddy?
天啊  我得交点新朋友了
Man, I gotta make some new friends